Guide to the Human Rights Watch Records: Helsinki Watch,
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
- Series VI: Ivana Nizich Files, 1990-1995
  - Croatia
    - International Cmte. of the Red Cross--Visits to Sibenik Prison, 1993 (Box 10, Folder 19)
    - Illegal Evictions, 1993-1994 (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - Indiscriminate Destruction of Civilian Property--Bombing, 1991-1992 (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - Institute for War and Peace Reporting, 1994-1995 (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - International Helsinki Federation for Human Rights, 1994-1995 (Box 11, Folder 4)
    - Interviews
      - Field Missions, 1993 (Box 11, Folder 5)
      - Public Figures, 1991-1992 (Box 11, Folder 6)
    - Jewish Community--General, 1991-1993 (Box 11, Folder 7)
    - JNA--General, 1991-1993 (Folder 8)
      - Information on Soldiers Given on Order of the Red Cross, undated (Box 11, Folder 9)
    - Journalists
      - Combat Related--Attacks on, 1991-1993 (Box 11, Folder 10)
      - Trials, 1992-1993 (Box 11, Folder 11)
    - Laura Pitter--News Clips, 1991-1995 (Box 11, Folder 12)
    - Laws
      - General, 1991-1993 (Box 12, Folder 1)
      - Laws of War, 1991-1992 (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - Lawyers Committee for Human Rights, 1993 (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - Maps, 1991-1993 (Box 12, Folder 4)
    - Medak Case, 1993 (Box 12, Folder 5)
    - Medical Targets, 1991 (Box 12, Folder 6)
    - Medical Violations, 1991-1992 (Box 12, Folder 7)
    - Missions (March-May, 1992), 1992 (Box 12, Folder 8)
    - Ministry of Interior, 1991 (Box 12, Folder 9)
    - Negotiations--Vance Missions, 1992 (Box 12, Folder 10)
    - Opinion Editorials, 1992-1993 (Box 12, Folder 11)
    - Osijek, 1991-1992 (Box 12, Folder 12)
    - Pakrac, 1991 (Box 12, Folder 13)
    - Paramilitiaries--General, 1991-1992 (Box 12, Folder 14)
    - Peace Groups, 1991-1992 (Box 12, Folder 15)
    - Political Parties
      - General, 1992-1993 (Box 13, Folder 1)
      - HDZ, 1991-1993 (Box 13, Folder 2)
      - HSLS Budisa/SNS, 1992 (Box 13, Folder 3)
      - HSP Paraga, 1991-1992 (Box 13, Folder 4)
      - SDP Racan, 1991-1992 (Box 13, Folder 5)
    - Press Clips
      - General, 1993-1994, (3 Folders) (Box 13, Folder 6-8)
      - Croatia, 1991-1995 (Box 13, Folder 9)
    - Prisoner Exchanges, 1992-1993 (Box 13, Folder 10)
    - Prisoners of War, undated (Box 13, Folder 11)
    - Propaganda, 1991-1993, (2 Folders) (Box 13, Folder 12-13)
    - Psychiatric Abuse, 1989-1992 (Box 13, Folder 14)
    - Recognition by
      - European Community, 1991-1993 (Box 13, Folder 15)
      - General, 1991-1992 (Box 13, Folder 16)
      - United States, 1991-1992 (Box 13, Folder 17)
    - Refugees
      - Bosnia, 1992-1993 (Box 13, Folder 18)
      - General, 1991-1992 (Box 13, Folder 19)
      - UNHCR, 1991-1992 (Box 13, Folder 20)
      - Used in 1994 Report, 1994 (Box 13, Folder 21)
    - Religion--Attacks
      - Religious Figures, 1991-1992 (Box 13, Folder 22)
      - Churches, 1991-1992 (Box 14, Folder 1)
      - Jews, 1992 (Box 14, Folder 2)
      - Serb Orthodox, 1991-1992 (Box 14, Folder 3)
    - Republic of Croatia
      - Ministry of Foreign Affairs--Newsletters, 1993-1994, (2 Folders) (Box 14, Folder 4-5)
      - Ministry of Information--Publications, 1992 (Box 14, Folder 6)
    - Succession, 1991 (Box 14, Folder 7)
    - Srpski Democratski Forum, 1992 (Box 14, Folder 8)
    - Srpski Glasnick, 1993 (Box 14, Folder 9)
    - Tudjman, 1993 (Box 14, Folder 10)
    - UN Operations in Bosnia-Herzegovina, 1993 (Box 14, Folder 11)
    - U.S. Policies
      - Congressional Report, 1991-1993 (Box 14, Folder 12)
      - Ethnic Conflict, 1992-1993 (Box 14, Folder 13)
      - U.S. State Dept. Briefings, 1991-1992 (Box 14, Folder 14)
      - U.S. State Dept. Country Reports, 1992-1993 (Box 14, Folder 15)
    - U.S. Committee for Refugees, 1992 (Box 14, Folder 16)
    - Used in 1994 Report, 1993-1994 (Box 14, Folder 17)
    - Victims of War in the Republic of Croatia, 1992 (Box 15, Folder 1)
    - Vukovar, 1991-1993 (Box 15, Folder 2)
    - War Crimes
      - Against Croatia Published by Vecernji, 1991 (Box 15, Folder 3)
      - Lists of Missing Persons, 1993-1994 (Box 15, Folder 4)
      - Trials--Serbs/JNA, 1992 (Box 15, Folder 5)
    - Weapons, 1992-1993 (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - Yugoslavia
    - Agression Definition, 1994 (Box 16, Folder 1)
    - AIM Review, 1994-1995 (Box 16, Folder 2)
    - Air Power, 1994 (Box 16, Folder 3)
    - Amnesty International--General, 1990-1995 (Box 16, Folder 4)
    - Amnesty Issue, 1995 (Box 16, Folder 5)
    - Arms Transfer, 1992-1993 (Box 16, Folder 6)
    - Balkan Peace Team Newsletter, 1994 (Box 16, Folder 7)
    - Bosnia
      - Amnesty International, 1993-1995 (Box 16, Folder 8)
      - Center for Constitutional Rights (CCR)--Doe v. Karadzic
        - Correspondence, 1993-1995 (Box 16, Folder 9)
        - Documents, 1993-1995 (Box 16, Folder 10-11)
        - Torture claim, 1993 (Box 16, Folder 12)
      - General, 1992-1993 (Box 16, Folder 13)
      - Helsinki Watch
        - Policy position, 1992 (Box 16, Folder 14)
        - Report: The Continuing Influence of Bosnia’s Warlords”, 1996 (Box 16, Folder 15)
      - Rape
        - General, 1992 (Box 16, Folder 16)
        - General, 1993 (Box 17, Folder 1)
        - Testimonies, 1992 (Box 17, Folder 2)
      - Soros Foundation--Open Society News, 1994 (Box 17, Folder 3)
      - Treatment of Prisoners, 1992 (Box 17, Folder 4)
    - Council of Europe, 1992-1994 (Box 17, Folder 5)
    - CSCE-OSCE
      - General, 1975-1995, (3 Folders) (Box 17, Folder 6-8)
      - Reports, 1990-1995 (Box 17, Folder 9)
    - Economic, social and cultural rights, 1987 (Box 18, Folder 1)
    - European Community, 1993 (Box 18, Folder 2)
    - European Convention on Human Rights, 1987-1992 (Box 18, Folder 3)
    - European Union, 1994-1995 (Box 18, Folder 4)
    - Forensic evidence, 1989-1994 (Box 18, Folder 5)
    - Genocide, undated (Box 18, Folder 6)
    - Helsinki Citizens’ Assembly, 1994 (Box 18, Folder 7)
    - Helsinki Watch
      - Articles, interviews, press clippings, 1990, 1994, (5 Folders) (Box 18, Folder 8-12)
      - Mission, 1992 (Box 18, Folder 13)
      - Press releases, reports, open letters, 1991-1992, (2 Folders) (Box 18, Folder 14-15)
      - Press releases, reports, open letters, 1993-1994, (3 Folders) (Box 19, Folder 1-3)
      - Testimonies, 1991 (Box 19, Folder 4)
    - Institute of Medicine: “The Impact of War on Child Health in the Countries of the Former Yugoslavia”, 1995 (Box 19, Folder 5)
    - International Court of Justice
      - Correspondence, 1993 (Box 19, Folder 6)
      - Documents, 1993, (3 Folders) (Box 19, Folder 7-9)
    - International Rescue Committee, 1995 (Box 19, Folder 10)
    - Interoffice Memos
      - Conscription in Israeli Occupied Lebanon, 1991 (Box 20, Folder 1)
      - Freedom of Speech Issues: HRW policy on Hate speech, 1991 (Box 20, Folder 2)
      - General, 1992-1995 (Box 20, Folder 3)
      - Homophobia: Gay Rights Policy, 1993 (Box 20, Folder 4)
      - Insulting the Head of State, 1993 (Box 20, Folder 5)
      - International Law Humanitarian Standards, 1979-1994, (3 Folders) (Box 20, Folder 6-8)
      - Minority language rights, 1984-1993 (Box 20, Folder 9)
      - Missions
        - Confidential mission notes, 1994 (Box 20, Folder 10)
        - Proposed procedures for dangerous missions, 1994 (Box 20, Folder 11)
      - Office manual: computer and e-mail instructions, 1994 (Box 20, Folder 12)
      - Police brutality, 1991-1992 (Box 20, Folder 13)
      - Training Sessions
        - Fact-finding and internal strife, 1991-1993 (Box 20, Folder 14)
        - Fact-finding: “Bearing Witness: The Art and Science of Human Rights Fact-Finding”, 1990 (Box 21, Folder 1)
        - Fact-Finding in prisons, 1984-1994 (Box 21, Folder 2)
        - Interviewing, 1991-1994 (Box 21, Folder 3)
        - Security problems, 1992 (Box 21, Folder 4)
        - Self-determination, 1986, 1991 (Box 21, Folder 5)
      - United Nations, 1994-1995 (Box 21, Folder 6)
      - United States
        - Human Rights law, 1992-1993 (Box 21, Folder 7)
        - Supreme Court, 1992 (Box 21, Folder 8)
      - World Bank, IMF information, 1991 (Box 21, Folder 9)
    - Investigatory methodology, 1983-1990 (Box 21, Folder 10)
    - Laws: international law, rules of war, 1993 (Box 21, Folder 11)
    - Lawyers Committee for Human Rights, 1991, 1993-1994 (Box 21, Folder 12)
    - Medicins Sans Frontieres, 1995 (Box 22, Folder 1)
    - Milosevic, Slobodan--Proposed civil suit, 1995 (Box 22, Folder 2)
    - National minorities, 1991-1993 (Box 22, Folder 3)
    - NATO: Implementation Force (IFOR), 1995 (Box 22, Folder 4)
    - OFAM: Briefing Paper on Yugoslavia, 1995 (Box 22, Folder 5)
    - Refugees--General, 1988-1994, (2 Folders) (Box 22, Folder 6-7)
    - Refugees International, 1993-1994 (Box 22, Folder 8)
    - Statelessness: Convention Relating to the Status of Stateless Persons, 1993 (Box 22, Folder 9)
    - Statistics, undated (Box 22, Folder 10)
    - United Nations
      - Commission of Experts, 1992-1994 (Box 22, Folder 11)
      - Commission on Human Rights, 1992-1994, (2 Folders) (Box 22, Folder 12-13)
      - Convention on the Elimination of All Forms of Discrimination Against Women, 1993 (Box 22, Folder 14)
      - Dayton Peace Agreement--General, 1995 (Box 22, Folder 15)
        - Full Text with Summary and Critique, 1995 (Box 23, Folder 1)
      - DHL UN/SA Reference on the former Yugoslavia, 1993-1994 (Box 23, Folder 2)
      - Documents, 1991-1995, (3 Folders) (Box 23, Folder 3-5)
      - General, 1994-1995 (Box 23, Folder 6)
      - General Assembly documents, 1992 (Box 23, Folder 7)
      - General Assembly documents, 1993-1995, (2 Folders) (Box 24, Folder 1-2)
      - Gentile, Louis: Report on the UN, 1994-1995 (Box 24, Folder 3)
      - Human Rights Committee, 1992-1994 (Box 24, Folder 4)
      - International Criminal Tribunal for the Former Yugoslavia
        - Articles, 1993-1995 (Box 24, Folder 5)
        - Correspondence, 1994-1995, (2 Folders) (Box 24, Folder 6-7)
        - Critique of Charter, 1993-1994 (Box 24, Folder 8)
        - Deferral of domestic cases to Tribunal, 1994-1995 (Box 24, Folder 9)
        - Financing, 1993-1994 (Box 24, Folder 10)
        - Financing, 1995 (Box 25, Folder 1)
        - Memos, 1992-1993, 1995, (3 Folders) (Box 25, Folder 2-4)
      - Mazowiecki, Tadeusz Special Rapporteur
        - Funding, 1994-1995 (Box 25, Folder 5)
        - Reports, 1992-1993 (Box 25, Folder 6)
        - Resignation, 1993-1995 (Box 25, Folder 7)
      - NATO: Policies towards the former Yugoslavia, 1994 (Box 25, Folder 8)
      - Peacekeeping, 1994-1995 (Box 25, Folder 9)
      - Sector-East--General, 1993, (2 Folders) (Box 25, Folder 10-11)
      - Sector West--Population census, 1993 (Box 26, Folder 1)
      - Security Council--Documents, 1992-1993, (6 Folders) (Box 26, Folder 2-7)
      - Security Council Documents, 1994-1995, (2 Folders) (Box 27, Folder 1-2)
        - Reference Papers: “UN and the Situation in the Former Yugoslavia”, 1992-1993 (Box 27, Folder 3)
    - UN High Commissioner for Refugees (UNHCR)
      - Daily Press Summary, 1995 (Box 27, Folder 4)
      - General, 1993-1995 (Box 27, Folder 5)
      - Information Notes on former Yugoslavia, 1993-1995, (2 Folders) (Box 27, Folder 6-7)
    - UNICEF, 1992-1994 (Box 27, Folder 8)
    - UN Protection Force (UNPROFOR)--General Information, 1992-1995, (2 Folders) (Box 27, Folder 9-10)
    - UN Protection Force (UNPROFOR)--General Information, 1995 (Box 28, Folder 1)
      - Lawyers Committee for Human Rights--Mission, 1993-1994 (Box 28, Folder 2)
    - United States--Department of State (DOS)--Country Reports, 1990-1993 (Box 28, Folder 3)
    - War Crimes Hearings, conferences, 1992-1995 (Box 28, Folder 4)
- Series VII: Chris Panico Files, 1979-1992
  A researcher for the Europe and Central Asia division of Human Rights Watch files his files are arranged alphabetically and consist of correspondence, manuscripts, memorandums, newspaper clippings, photographs and research reports.
  - Armenia
    - Ayrikyan, Parvir (Armenian nationalist, human rights monitor), 1988 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Deportees--Armenian--Interviews, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Government, 1990-1991, (3 Folders) (Box 1, Folder 3-5)
    - Karabagh Conflict, 1990-1991 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Press Clips, 1987-1992, (2 Folders) (Box 2, Folder 1-2)
  - Azerbaijan
    - Background Information, 1988-1990 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Baltic States
    - Committee to Protect Journalists--Report: Killing the Messengers: Lithuania and Latvia, 1991 January (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Press Clips, 1988-1991 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Radio Free Europe/Radio Liberty Report, 1991 May-August (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Recognition--Baltic States, 1991 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Ukraine
    - Background, 1987-1989, (2 Folders) (Box 3, Folder 2-3)
    - Ukrainian Catholic Church, 1988-1990 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Ukrainian Helsinki Group, 1988-1989 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - USSR
    - AIDS, 1987-1990 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - American Bar Association (ABA)--ABA-ASL Seminar (Association of Soviet Lawyers (ASL) Delegation), 1988 October 19-20) (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - American Committee on U.S.-Soviet Relations--New Outlook Quarterly, 1990-1991 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Anreyeva, Nina--Incident--“I Cannot Sacrifice My Principles,” Sovetskaya Rossiya (1988 March), 1988-1989 (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Anti-Soviet Memorial, 1988-1990 (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - Arts, 1981-1990 (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - Break-up of, 1991 (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - Cases--Prisoners, 1989 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Censorship, 1990 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Chernobyl, 1989-1990 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Christian Care East, 1988 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Civil Society Report--General, 1987-1989 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Committee to Protect Journalists--Report: The Soviet Media’s Year of Decision, 1991 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Communist Party, 1988-1990 (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Conscientious Objectors, 1989-1990 (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Constitution--Belarusian, 1989 (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - Constitutional Amendments Law, 1988 (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - Contacts, 1987-1990 (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - Correspondents--Journalists, 1985-1987 (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - Coup
      - General, 1991-1991, (3 Folders) (Box 4, Folder 13-15)
      - General, 1991-1991, (3 Folders) (Box 5, Folder 1-3)
      - Post-Coup Aftermath, 1991 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Crime, 1989-1991 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Crimean Tatars, 1987-1990 (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - Criminal Code (Draft), 1989 (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - CSCE
    - Conference--Helsinki--Statements, 1992 (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Conference--Moscow, 1987-1991 (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - Conference--Moscow, 1991, (2 Folders) (Box 6, Folder 1-2)
    - Conference--Moscow--Statements, 1991 (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - Daily Glasnost, 1989-1990 (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Death Penalty, 1987-1990 (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Democratic Perestroika, 1989 (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Democratic Platform Conference--CPSU, 1990 (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - Democratic Union, 1988-1989 (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - Demonstrations, 1988-1990 (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - Dissent--Human Rights--General, 1987 (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - Economic Conditions, 1989 (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - Economic Planning, 1990 (Box 6, Folder 12)
    - Economic Reforms, 1991 (Box 6, Folder 13)
    - Education, 1988-1989 (Box 6, Folder 14)
    - Emigration
      - General, 1988-1991 (Box 6, Folder 15)
      - Law, 1991 May (Box 6, Folder 16)
    - Emigres, 1979-1990, (3 Folders) (Box 7, Folder 1-3)
    - Environment
      - General, 1988-1992 (Box 7, Folder 4)
      - Environmental Groups, 1988-1989 (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Estonia, 1984-1991 (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - Exchanges, 1988 (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Family Reunification, 1988-1989 (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Fascists, undated (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Forced Labor, 1985-1987 (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - Freedom of Information, 1988-1989 (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - Georgia
      - Correspondence, 1989 (Box 8, Folder 6)
      - Georgian Helsinki Group, 1987 (Box 8, Folder 7)
      - Press Clips, 1989-1990 (Box 8, Folder 8)
      - South Ossetia
        - Mission--Notebook, 1991 (Box 8, Folder 9)
        - Mission--Report (Draft)--Related Materials, 1990-1992 (Box 8, Folder 10)
        - Mission--Research Material, 1979-1991 (Box 8, Folder 11)
        - Press Clips, 1991-1992 (Box 8, Folder 12)
    - Germans--Ethnic, 1981-1989 (Box 8, Folder 13)
    - Glasnost Magazine, 1987-1988 (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - Grigoryants, Sergei (dissident, journalist), 1988-1989 (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - Health Conditions, 1988-1989 (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - History, 1986-1989 (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - Homosexuality, 1989-1990 (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - Hospital Lists, undated (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - Human Rights--Hearings on Human Rights in the USSR, 1991 September 7-8 (Box 9, Folder 7)
    - Independent Publications, 1987-1990 (Box 9, Folder 8)
    - “Informal” Political Groups and Parties, 1989 (Box 9, Folder 9)
    - Interlegal Research Center--Human Rights, 1992 (Box 9, Folder 10)
    - International Helsinki Federation (IHF)
      - General, 1986-1990 (Box 9, Folder 11)
      - Mission--Moscow (1988), 1987-1989, (2 Folders) (Box 9, Folder 12-13)
    - Inter-Regional Group (IRG), 1989-1990 (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - Jews, 1990-1991 (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - Kazachkov, Mikhail (editor, dissident), 1989-1990 (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - Kazakhstan, 1989-1990 (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - KGB, 1988-1989 (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - Kuznetsov, Sergei (independent journalist), 1989-1989 (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - Labor
      - Camps, 1987-1990 (Box 10, Folder 7)
      - Law, 1990-1990 (Box 10, Folder 8)
    - Law Texts
      - Drafts--Informal, 1989 (Box 10, Folder 9)
      - Drafts--Official, 1988-1990 (Box 10, Folder 10)
      - Law Texts--Final, 1989-1991 (Box 10, Folder 11)
    - Lawyers Committee for Human Rights
      - Briefing Papers, 1991 (Box 10, Folder 12)
      - Memoranda, 1989-1991 (Box 10, Folder 13)
    - Legal Analysis
      - General, 1987-1988 (Box 10, Folder 14)
      - General, 1989-1990 (2 files) (Box 11, Folder 1-2)
    - Legal Commentary
      - General, 1988-1990 (Box 11, Folder 3)
      - Helsinki Watch, 1988-1990 (Box 11, Folder 4)
      - Human Rights Groups--Other, 1988-1989 (Box 11, Folder 5)
      - Human Rights Groups--Soviet, 1989-1991 (Box 11, Folder 6)
      - Soviet Press, 1989-1990 (Box 11, Folder 7)
      - U.S. Press, 1989-1990 (Box 11, Folder 8)
    - Legal Conference: Legal Reform in the Soviet Union: Prospects for Human Rights. 1990 November 14-15 (Box 11, Folder 9)
    - Lithuania
      - Lithuanian Catholics, 1989 (Box 11, Folder 10)
      - Lithuanian Independence
        - Correspondence, 1990 March (Box 11, Folder 11)
        - Press Clips, 1990 (Box 11, Folder 12)
      - Press Clips
        - General, 1984-1987 (Box 11, Folder 13)
        - General, 1988-1990 (2 files) (Box 12, Folder 1-2)
      - Soviet Military Occupation--Human Rights Violations--Official Statements, 1991 (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - Military
      - Amnesty--Draft Dodgers, 1991 (Box 12, Folder 4)
      - Military--Russia, 1988-1992 (Box 12, Folder 5)
    - Ministry of Internal Affairs (MVD), 1988-1990 (Box 12, Folder 6)
    - Moscow Helsinki Group, 1990 (Box 12, Folder 7)
    - Moscow Independent University, 1988-1989 (Box 12, Folder 8)
    - Moscow Tribune Club, 1989 (Box 12, Folder 9)
    - Moscow Trust Group
      - General, 1986-1987 (Box 12, Folder 10)
      - Moscow Trust Group, 1987, 1989, (2 Folders) (Box 13, Folder 1-2)
    - Muslims, 1984-1989 (Box 13, Folder 3)
    - Nagorno-Karabagh
      - Mission--Notebook, 1992 (Box 13, Folder 4)
      - War--“Operation Ring”
        - Reports, 1991 (Box 13, Folder 5)
        - Statistics, 1991 (Box 13, Folder 6)
      - War--Trans-Caucasus Region
        - Correspondence, 1991-1992 (Box 13, Folder 7)
        - Press Accounts, 1991, (2 Folders) (Box 14, Folder 1-2)
        - Reports, 1991 (Box 14, Folder 3)
    - National Endowment for Democracy, 1988-1989 (Box 14, Folder 4)
    - Nationalities, 1986-1990 (Box 14, Folder 5)
    - Orlov, Yuri (nuclear physicist, dissent, human rights activist), 1989 (Box 14, Folder 6)
    - “Ostashvili” Case, 1992 (Box 14, Folder 7)
    - Pamyat (Trans: “Memory”), 1988-1990 (Box 14, Folder 8)
    - “Panorama” (news weekly), 1991-1992 (Box 14, Folder 9)
    - Peace Mailing, 1988 (Box 14, Folder 10)
    - Pentecostals, 1988 (Box 14, Folder 11)
    - People’s Labor Organization (NTS), 1989 (Box 14, Folder 12)
    - Perm Labor Camp
      - Prisoner Information, 1988-1990 (Box 14, Folder 13)
        [restricted until 2966]
      - Prisoner Information, 1988-1990 (Box 15, Folder 1)
    - Postfactum (independent news agency), 1990 (Box 15, Folder 2)
    - Press--Freedom of the Press, 1990-1991 (Box 15, Folder 3)
    - Press--Press Law, 1989-1990 (Box 15, Folder 4)
    - Press Club Glasnost
      - General, 1987-1989 (Box 15, Folder 5)
      - Conference (December 10-15, 1987), 1987 (Box 15, Folder 6)
    - Prisoners
      - Current, 1987-1982, (2 Folders) (Box 15, Folder 7-8)
      - Letter-writing Campaigns, 1987-1991 (Box 15, Folder 9)
    - Prisons
      - General, 1989-1991 (Box 15, Folder 10)
      - Prison Projects, 1989-1992 (Box 16, Folder 1)
    - Prosecutors, 1990-1990 (Box 16, Folder 2)
    - Psychiatry
      - General, 1989-1991 (Box 16, Folder 3)
      - Independent Psychiatric Association, 1986-1989 (Box 16, Folder 4)
      - International Association on the Political Use of Psychiatry
        - Documents on the Political Abuse of Psychiatry in the USSR (English), 1988-1991, (4 Folders) (Box 16, Folder 5-8)
        - Documents on the Political Abuse of Psychiatry in the USSR (Russian), 1989-1991, (3 Folders) (Box 16, Folder 9-11)
        - Information Bulletin, 1986-1989 (Box 16, Folder 12)
      - American Psychiatric Association--American Delegation, 1989 February-March (Box 16, Folder 13)
    - Psychiatry--Abuse
      - Assessment of Recent Changes in Soviet Psychiatry, 1989 (Box 17, Folder 1)
      - Cases, 1985-1990 (Box 17, Folder 2)
      - General, 1989-1990 (Box 17, Folder 3)
      - Human Rights Watch--Report, 1990 May (Box 17, Folder 4)
      - Law, 1988 (Box 17, Folder 5)
      - Press--United States, 1989-1990 (Box 17, Folder 6)
      - Press--USSR, 1989 (Box 17, Folder 7)
      - Soviet Delegation, 1990 (Box 17, Folder 8)
      - World Psychiatric Association, 1989 (Box 17, Folder 9)
    - Public Human Rights Commission--Soviet, 1988-1990 (Box 17, Folder 10)
    - Reference--Contacts and Organizations, 1988 (Box 17, Folder 11)
    - Refugees
      - General, 1988-1990 (Box 17, Folder 12)
      - Draft Law, undated (Box 17, Folder 13)
    - Religion
      - Bulletin of Christian Opinion, 1988-1989 (Box 17, Folder 14)
      - Freedom of Religion, 1987-1989 (Box 18, Folder 1)
      - General, 1987-1991 (Box 18, Folder 2)
      - Law, 1990 (Box 18, Folder 3)
    - Republic Secession Law, 1990 (Box 18, Folder 4)
    - Resistance, 1987 (Box 18, Folder 5)
    - Russian Orthodox Church, 1988-1990 (Box 18, Folder 6)
    - Russian Soviet Federated Socialist Republic (RSFSR)--Constitution
      - Correspondence, 1990 (Box 18, Folder 7)
      - Draft, 1991 (Box 18, Folder 8)
    - Sakharov, Andrei D. (1921-1989) (nuclear physicist, dissident), 1984, 1987-1990, (3 Folders) (Box 18, Folder 9-11)
    - Sakharov, Elena Bonner--Statement: “The Helsinki Act in the Future”, 1991 September 10 (Box 18, Folder 12)
    - Samizdat
      - Moscow-based journals and publications, undated (Box 18, Folder 13)
      - Moscow Information Exchange Bureau (MBIO), 1989 (Box 18, Folder 14)
      - The Samizdat Bulletin, 1988-1989 (Box 18, Folder 15)
    - Scientists, 1987-1990 (Box 18, Folder 16)
    - Seventh Day Adventists, 1988 (Box 18, Folder 17)
    - Siberia, 1988-1989 (Box 18, Folder 18)
    - Slepak Principles, 1988-1990 (Box 19, Folder 1)